Guide to the Time Inc. Entertainment Weekly Task Force Records 1986-1988 (bulk 1988) MS 3009-RG 59
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Entertainment Weekly Task Force records
1986-1988 (bulk 1988)
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 59
2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
Time Inc. studied the concept of what became Entertainment Weekly for years before actually publishing the magazine. A Task Force on Entertainment Weekly was formed to study every aspect of the proposed magazine including editorial direction and content, projections on advertising and circulation, and to perform direct-mail tests to gauge consumer interest in the magazine.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
The Time Inc. Entertainment Weekly Task Force Records are arranged in alphabetical order.
Historical Note
The concept of a weekly magazine assessing readers' entertainment options arose at Time Inc. in 1988 almost simultaneously with Mike Klingensmith and Jeff Jarvis, who then collaborated to develop the concept that became Entertainment Weekly. Time Inc. spent two years studying and testing the concept which included the formation of a Task Force on Entertainment Weekly. This task force studied the proposed magazine's advertising potential, editorial direction, researched competing magazines, and performed direct mail marketing tests including soliciting subscriptions before the magazine was ready to be published, and created plans and reports based on their findings. Entertainment Weekly began publication in 1990.
Citation:
Time Inc. Subject Files, MS 3009-RG 1, New-York Historical Society.
Custodial History
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Further material on the earliest days of Entertainment Weekly can be found in the Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3). Further material on Michael Klingensmith can be found in the Time Inc. Bio Files (MS 3009-RG 2).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records belonging to Mike Klingensmith, then Chief Financial Officer of the Magazine Group and future Publisher of Entertainment Weekly, and Nancy Phillips, Business Manager of Life and member of the task force. It includes projections on pricing, costs, circulation growth, advertising, and other forms of planning for the launch of Entertainment Weekly as a new magazine such as direct mail advertisements, samples of other magazines, and proposals on the concept of the magazine and general style of editorial content. There is a small amount of reference material pre-dating the Task Force on Entertainment Weekly including an earlier Time Inc. study on a new magazine concept.
Corporation records.; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- 4RT Back-Up, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 1)
- Ad Sales Plan, undated (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 2)
- Advertising Plan, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 3)
- Agency, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 4)
- Agency Expenses, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 5)
- Alternate Source Development, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 6)
- Background Reading, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 7)
- Business Plan, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 8)
- Business Plan Proposal, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 9)
- Circulation Plan/General, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 10-11)
- Competition, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 12)
- Cost and Income Estimates, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 13)
- Delivery Schedule, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 14)
- Direct Mail Test, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 15)
- Editorial, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 16)
- Editorial Plan, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 17)
- Estimated Year 6, undated (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 18)
- Final Expenses, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 19)
- Focus Group: Currents, 1986 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 20)
- Focus Groups, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 21)
- General, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 22)
- Interview Notes/Other Notes, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 23)
- Magazine Samples, 1988 (Offsite-box 4294, Folder 24-26)
- Magee Model Backup, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 1)
- Model Runs, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 2)
- Newsstand Run, undated (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 3)
- Originals, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 4)
- Pricing, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 5)
- Pricing Run, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 6)
- Product Development, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 7)
- A Profile of Entertainment Weekly Respondents, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 8)
- Project Nancy Phillips, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 9)
- Qualitative Research About Entertainment Weekly, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 10)
- Report of the Task Force, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 11-12)
- Research, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 13)
- Schedule, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 14)
- Subscriber Survey, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 15)
- TOS/Newsstand Plan, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 16)
- TV Assumptions, 1988 (Offsite-box 4295, Folder 17)